Now we can only trust them
今はただ彼らを信じるしかない
Your Highness
殿下でんか
The western neighbor seems to be moving
西側の隣国に動きがある疑いがある
How can Your Highness suppress this news
殿下はどうして情報を抑えられるのでしょうか
And not let His Majesty recall troops to defend
陛下に兵を退かせて守備に戻らせない
Minister Xue
セツ大人
Father has planned this battle for half his life
父はこの戦いのために半生を費やして策略を練った
You have no solid evidence
大人には確かな証拠がない
How can I issue such an order?
私にどうやってそんな命令を出せと言うのですか
We're not afraid of the unlikely
私たちは一万でも怖くない
But the one in ten thousand, Your Highness
万が一の場合が心配です殿下
If we wait for solid evidence before sending troops
兵を出すようなことは確かな証拠が揃うまで待つべきだ
Wouldn't it be too late?
それはまだ遅くない
Your Highness is considerate of the Emperor
殿下は皇帝を思いやっています
But now the country's defenses are empty
しかし今や国内の守備は手薄である
If the enemy truly invades
もし敵軍が国境を侵したなら
And we suffer defeat
敗北を喫する
Will His Majesty be considerate of Your Highness?
陛下は殿下のことをお察しになれますか
There were heavy rains in the southern border
南疆では数回の大雨が降った
Which reduced your embezzlement by a bit
大人には油を少し減らしてあげる
So you can't do this job anymore?
この仕事はもうできない
Minister Xue, do you think I'm young and easy to bully
薛殿は私が年若くて侮りやすいと思っている
And know nothing?
何も知らないのですか
Your Highness, everything I do is for Great Xuan
殿下私はすべて大宣のために尽くします
Your servant is willing to remonstrate with death
私は命をかけて諫言したい
Minister Xue, you mustn't
薛大人それは駄目ですよ
Your Highness
殿下でんか
We cannot treat Great Xuan's fate as a game
国の隆盛を子供の遊びのように扱ってはいけない
Lady Chen, what brings you here?
陳夫人これは何のために来たのですか
Since Minister Xue wants to remonstrate with death
薛卿は死をもって助言したい
Go help him
彼を助けに行って
Yes
です
Chen Wan'er
チェンワンアール
You
あなた
You dare kill a senior minister in the Taiji Hall
あなたは太極殿で重臣を勝手に殺す勇気があるのか
Do you really think His Majesty will tolerate you later?
あなたは本当に陛下が今後あなたを許してくれると思っているのか
Whether he tolerates me
受け入れられますか
Is a matter between His Majesty and me as husband and wife
それは私と陛下との夫婦の問題です
You're old
おじいさんはもう年を取っています
Still so nosy
まだそんなに簡単に聞けるのか
The Crown Prince is overseeing the court
皇太子が朝廷で政務を執り行っている
His Majesty is personally leading the campaign
陛下はさらにご自身で出陣なさった
My son has the courage to fight on the front lines
私の息子にはまだ前線で戦う勇気があります
The Chen family is not panicking
陳家は慌てていない
Gentlemen
皆さん
What are you panicking about?
何を慌てているの
The decisive battle between Great Xuan and Wuzhao
大宣と邬伖の決戦
Is in these few days
ちょうどこの数日間に
You gentlemen shall stay in the palace as guests
皆さまひとまず宮中にお泊まりください
I will personally host you
本宮自らおもてなしする
Before the battle is settled
戦争が落ち着く前に
Anyone who passes through this gate
この門を通る者はすべて
Kill
殺す
Those who speak cunningly of retreat
狡猾な言葉で退く者
Those who harm the state for personal gain
私利で国を誤る者
Kill
殺す
Yes
です
Raise my royal banner in the formation
私の王旗を陣中に立てよ
Send all the imperial guard
親衛隊を全部派遣しろ
Today
今日
We must not let him escape
絶対に逃がしてはいけない
Yes
はい
Imperial Guard
親衛隊
Follow me and kill
私と一緒に殺して
Kill
殺す
Sikong Yao
シクウヨウ
Today is the life-and-death battle between you and me
今日こそ我々の生死をかけた戦いだ
Report
報
My King
王
Something's wrong
まずい
Xuan troops are attacking from behind
宣軍が後方から襲ってきた
Cutting off our retreat
我々軍の退路を断った
What?
何
Follow me to cut off their retreat
私が彼らの退路を断った後に続け
Brother
弟
Let's retreat
俺たち撤退しよう
I fell into an ambush
俺は待ち伏せに引っかかった
This time, I fell into an ambush
今度は俺が罠にかかった
Let's regroup
私たちは再び勢いを取り戻す
Brother
弟
If not for you, for your son
もしあなたがあの息子のためでなければ
Not following my orders
俺の号令を聞かない
And engaging the enemy on your own
私は自ら敵を迎え撃つ
How could we have come to this today?
今日はどうしてこんなことになったのか
Brother
弟
Don't
やめて
My empire was destroyed by you
俺の覇業はお前の手で滅ぼされた
Brother
弟
Recall the vanguard
前の軍隊を呼び戻す
Break through from the rear
後方から突破する
Yes
です